Eva Sharma

Tech Square Research Building (341A) 85 Fifth Street NW, Atlanta GA 30308

♥ evasharma@gatech.edu

☎ (607) 379-8985

♣ cc.gatech.edu/~esharma8

Aug 2016 - Present

GPA 4.0 / 4.0

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interests are in the area of computational social sciences and I aim to leverage computational methods and resources in order to understand and reason about complex social processes underlying human behavior in large-scale online social systems.

Topics: Social Computing, Computational Social Science, Large-Scale Data Analysis, Online Communities, Online Social Support

EDUCATION

Georgia Institute Of Technology, Atlanta, GA Doctor of Philosophy, Advisor: Munmun De Choudhury Computer Science.

Cornell University, Ithaca, NY
Masters of Engineering,
Computer Science.

Aug 2014 - May 2015
GPA 3.9 / 4.0

Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, MA
Bachelors of Technology (Semester Abroad Program),
Electrical Engineering and Computer Science.

Aug 2011 - Jan 2012
GPA 5.0 / 5.0

SRM University, Chennai, TN, India
Bachelors of Technology,
Computer Science (Gold Medalist).

Jul 2009 - May 2013
GPA 9.9 / 10.0

PUBLICATIONS

Analyzing Ideological discourse on Social Media: A Case Study of the Abortion Debate Jan 2017 Submitted to ICWSM 2017.

Eva Sharma, Koustuv Saha, Sindhu Kiranmai Ernala, Sucheta Ghoshal, Munmun De Choudhury

CURRENT PROJECTS

Social Support in Online Mental Health Communities

Oct 2016 - Present

Munmun De Choudhury

- Quantify Informational and Emotional Support in Reddit Mental Health Communities.
- Find Linguistic Alignment between posts receiving respective amount of support.
- Analyze Reddit Mental Health Communities' helpfulness, efficacy, and survival over time.

Qualitative Study on ShitRedditSays(SRS)

Nov 2016 - Present

Amy S. Bruckman

- Interviewed Reddit users who are shamed on SRS.
- Analyze accounts of SRS members as well as Reddit users shamed on SRS to understand the significance and impact of SRS on the rest of Reddit.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Oracle, Cambridge, MA

Software Developer II

Jul 2015 - Aug 2016

• Implemented Multiple Payment and Address Book Module for Mobile Commerce iOS Application

SAP Labs India Pvt. Ltd. Bangalore, India

Associate Developer

Jul 2013 - Jul 2014

• Worked on Software Logistics Process Repository for Lifecycle Management of SAP Software

- Designed and implemented installation and update feature for HANA Application Lifecycle Management
- Co-Implemented delete and copy stack backend functionality for Cross Product Stack Editor

Intern Feb 2013 - Jun 2013

- Analyzed Customer Profile Data in XML format by automating processing of XMLs and feeding them to HANA database where the data can be later visualized as graphs
- Built an interface which utilizes gestures and voice to interact with computers.

TEACHING

Cornell University, Ithaca, NY

Spring 2015

Teaching Assistant

Prof. Lucja Kot, CS 4320/5320 Introduction to Database System

PAST PROJECTS

Semantic Legal Information System's

Jan 2015 - May 2015

Legal Text Indexing Application

Sara S. Frug, Legal Information Institute, Cornell University

- Studied and experimented with Topic Modeling for CFR Corpus
- Used metadata from CFR and FR corpus to capture evolution of a topic over time
- Employed incremental modeling and phrase extraction using Mallet

Computing a statistical description of 3-D structure of nano-scale biological objects

Oct 2014 - Dec 2014

Prof. Peter Charles Doerschuk, Cornell University

- Helped providing python conversion of MATLAB equivalent of fmincon, which solves nonlinear programming problems, fundamentally computing the location of the minimum value of a user-provided function
- Applied MATLAB version of the project to example problems to determine the input values for each of the project's functions and the returned values.
- Wrote unit test cases in python to perform extensive testing for the python version of the project

Sound Source Localization

Sep 2011 - Dec 2011

Massachusetts Institute of Technology

Prof. James R Glass, Spoken Language System Group, CSAIL

- Studied various techniques being used for 2-D acoustic localization
- Implemented GCC-PHAT method to localize sound using two microphones MATLAB

ACHIEVEMENTS AND AWARDS

- Undergraduate Gold Medalist, Awarded by The Prime Minister of India, Mr. Narendra Modi
- Undergraduate Toppers Scholarship, Perfect GPA of 10.0/10.0 Award for 3rd, 6th and 8th semesters
- Undergraduate sponsorship for a semester abroad at Massachusetts Institute of Technology, USA

EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Presented poster on "Quantifying Well-Being Support to Assess Efficacy of Online Communities" in GVU Fall Research Showcase 2016, Georgia Institute of Technology.
- Presented poster on "Semantic Legal Information Systems Improving Access to Regulatory Information" in BOOM 2015 (BITS ON OUR MINDS), Cornell University.
- Volunteered for Product Innovation Day Event in SAP Labs, Bangalore.
- Participated in Hadoop Tech Talk conducted at Exebit 2012, IIT Madras.
- Participated in Ethical Hacking and Information Security Workshop by Kyrion Technologies.
- Organized Paper Presentation event held at Infoyez11, SRM University, Chennai.